Nasser Alawami

Nationality: Saudi LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/NasserAlawami/

+966 **56 000 7701** Email: NasserAlawami@gmail.com Mobile:

Professional Summary

Experienced Information Technology professional with 5+ years' experience in leading in-person and remote teams. Seeks to employ top-class skills at reputable organization. In current role, improved team's effectiveness by 25% via identifying and resolving a bottleneck.

Certified Project Management Professional Project Management



- Six Sigma Green Belt Certified
- Customer Relationship Management
- Innovative, competitive, and self-motivated
- Team Player and a Team Leader
- Strong judgment, critical and strategic thinking abilities
- Very quick to adapt

Experiences

09/2020 - Present

Operations Excellence Team Lead at RASAN Information Technology



- Key member of the Operations Excellence department and Team leader
- Manage the day-to-day running of business operations
- Enhance the customer experience and ensure smooth and efficient service delivery
- Improving internal and external clients' processes

03/2018 - 10/2019

Project Management Strategic Initiatives,

SAP Digital Business Services 'DBS' Middle East North

- As a Project Management Officer at SAP DBS Office, I lead and collaborated with team members to conduct multiple projects
- SAP Multi-Resources Scheduling (MRS) and SAP Cloud implementation
- and SAP HANA Enterprise Cloud (HEC) Migration projects for power and water utility government owned company (MARAFIQ)
- Verified work achieved during all project phases
- SAP market unit Strategic Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) holder
- Created a dashboard system using excel, which aimed to track and verify the progress of each of the KPIs and the overall impact
- Managed the KPIs with local and global teams; and delivered outstanding results
- SAP Global Experience Management Engineering (XME) Office as SAP Experience Management Ambassador (XMA)
- Completed training and got certified as SAP Activate Project Manager

11/2017 - 02/2018

Business Process Consultant at SAP



- SAP Young Professionals Program(YPP) award winner
- Completed in-person SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central (EC) and SAP Ariba Procure to Pay (P2P) trainings and became certified in the solutions
- Completed a world class Communication and presentation skills by Alan Carroll and Associates
- Trained by SAP professionals for Internal SAP sales cycle and Design Thinking workshops with focus on business model courses

09/2017 - 11/2017

English, Computer and Math. Instructor in Tahtheeb Private Schools

Taught and Educated students in Mathematics, English, and Computer, applying a variety of instructional techniques, including hands-on curriculum. Furthermore, I communicated regularly with parents and guardians about student progress, working to involve parents in educational goals.

Certifications

PMP "Project Management Professional" Certified from Project Management Institute



- Six Sigma Green Belt Certified Professional by The Knowledge Academy
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) by SCRUM study
- Google Developer Day: IoT, Flutter, ML Google Cloud Developer Saudi Community
- SAP Certified Associate SAP Activate Project Manager
- Certified Blockchain Expert by Blockchain council
- SAP Certified Application Associate **SAP Ariba Procurement**
- SAP Certified Application Associate SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central
- The Basics of Data for Analytics by LinkedIn
- Industrial Safety Basics by Jubail Technical Institute
- Completed 40 training hours for RMP "Risk Management Professional" certification

Education

2013-2016, University of Wyoming, USA



B.S. In Computer Science

Graduated on the 12th of August 2016

Skills and Strong points

- Highly organized and meticulous IT Professional
- Data Infographics and visualization
- Problem solving and Design Thinking
- Great communicator and planner.
- SAP Customer Relation Management (CRM)
- SAP Activate Project Management.
- Hands-on experience with hardware and software
- Eclipse, Aptana Studio, Code Blocks, Microsoft Office programs, such as Excel, Word, and PowerPoint.
- Client-Side web programming; using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Basics of Computer Networking

Language Skills:

- Confident in addressing small and large audiences; presented multiple times using a variety of techniques such as: PowerPoint, Online Live Presentations (Teams, ZOOM, Skype)
- Solid writing skills in both Arabic and English Languages

Community Volunteer/Member

2020 - Present Member of the Project Management Institute (PMI)

2020 - Present Ministry of Health Volunteer

SAP Experience Management Ambassador. 2018 - Present

2018 - Present SAP Alumni network.

2013 - Present Member of the National Society of Collegiate and Scholars.

2011 King Fahad University of Petroleum and Minerals public services day.

Additional Highlights

- Senior Design Project: NASA RASC-AL Robo-Ops;
 - During the project I worked with in the Computer Science team alongside Mechanical Engineering, and Electrical Engineering teams. We worked in parallel in designing, planning, and executing the project.
- Highly self-motivated, hardworking, flexible, and reliable.
- Absorbing and learning new materials in a short period.
- Outgoing and a friendly person with great team work skills.
- Ability to develop strong relationships with co-workers and clients.

Interests and activities

Technology, Marketing, Social-Media, Traveling, Designing, Photography.